Indiana University Vice President and Chancellor's records, 1963-1976 C132
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Vice President and Chancellor's records
1963-1976
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. Vice President of the Bloomington Campus
C132
21 cubic feet 21 boxes
Byrum E. Carter was appointed Chancellor of Indiana University in 1969, after serving over two decades as an IU faculty member. Carter also played an important role in the political dynamics on campus during the heat of the Vietnam War. This collection is comprised of correspondence, reports, and administrative files dating primarily from Carter's years as Chancellor and Vice President of Indiana University's Bloomington campus, between July 1969 and June 1975.
Access Restrictions
Select files closed to researchers. These are indicated in the finding aid.
Advance notice required for access to collection.
Administrative History
A native Oklahoman, Byrum Earl Carter Jr. was born on March 3, 1922. Shortly before the outbreak of World War II, Carter began working towards his B.A. from Frederick Jr. College, however quickly his studies were interrupted by service in the Marine Corps and as a wage rate analyst for the War Labor Board. Following his discharge in 1943, Carter returned to his studies and in 1943 his received his B.A. from Oklahoma University. In 1945, he enrolled in the Wisconsin University where he began to work towards his Ph.D. and in 1947 he joined the faculty of Indiana University in the Department of Government. Upon the completion of his Ph.D. in 1951, he became a Junior Faculty member and over the course of the next decade he rose through the ranks, achieving the status of Full professor in 1960.
In 1959, Carter began working his way the administrative ranks of the university as the Assistant Dean of Faculties, in 1963 he was named the Acting Dean of Faculties, Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences in 1966, and in July of 1969 following a large-scale reorganization of the state-wide University he was named by the Board of Trustees as the Chancellor of the Indiana University Bloomington campus. Among the duties noted for this new post were: Campus academic program development, campus budget development, recruitment, promotion, tenure, retention, and termination of faculty and staff members, enforcement of rules and regulations pertaining to students and faculty, supervision of student services, library development and coordination and other duties as prescribed by the President.
Carter presided over the Bloomington campus during a period of great unrest, large-scale student demonstrations such as the 1969 boycott, the Ballantine Lock-In and those relating to the ongoing Vietnam War. Additionally, Carter was known for his discussion of the impact of veterans in the student population after World War II, the growth of the university and its graduate programs, and campus politics.
On June 29, 1974 under the presidency of John W. Ryan the board of trustees again ratified a massive reorganization of the university system. The Bloomington and Indianapolis campuses were designated as the "core" of the Indiana University multi-campus system with responsibilities split between the Chancellors of Bloomington and Indianapolis, whose titles were changed to "Vice President" of their respective campuses to reflect their new responsibilities. The Vice President of the Bloomington campus oversaw the: College of Arts and Sciences, Graduate School, School of Music, Indiana University School of Law, Graduate Library School, School of Health, Physical Education, and Recreation. The Vice President of the Indianapolis campus oversaw the Health related professional schools, School of Social Services, School of Business, School of Public and Environmental Affairs, Indianapolis School of Law, School of Continuing Education, School of Liberal Arts, Herron School of Arts, School of Science (in conjunction with Purdue), School of Engineering and Technology (in conjunction with Purdue).
In addition to his administrative role, Byrum Carter was also noted for his scholarship and work within the classroom. In 1956, he was awarded the Faculty Research fellowship for his study, "The Political Theory of John Stuart Mill;" his book, The Office of the Prime Minister (Princeton University Press, 1957) became a New York Times best seller, and in 1957 he was awarded the Fredric Bachman Lieber Memorial Award for teaching.
Carter resigned from the office of the Vice President of Bloomington in June of 1975 and on September 12, 1975, Robert M. O'Neil was appointed to the office. Carter finished his career in the Department of Political Science and retired from IU in December 1986 with the title Professor Emeritus of Political Science.
Carter was married to Beth Peter in 1944 and they had two children Terry Elizabeth (Mrs. Robert Hedrick) and son Casey Keith Madison.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: Administrative subject files and Logs of incoming correspondence. The Administrative subject files are arranged alphabetically and the Logs of incoming correspondence are arranged chronologically by month and year.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists primarily of administrative records, memoranda, and internal and external correspondence pertaining to departments within the university, committees, and matters of general university concern and a small portion of Logs of incoming correspondence dated between July and December of 1973. This collection primarily focuses on Carter's years as Chancellor and Vice President of Indiana University's Bloomington campus, between July 1969 and June 1975. The collection is organized into two series, Administrative subject files and Incoming correspondence logs.
Separated Material
Some files held one or two records with restricted information. In order to provide access to the other records, these were separated from the files and placed at the end of the collection in restricted folders.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
Acquisition numbers: 0311, 0631, 0644, 0998, 2095-2104, 1223, 2260-2264, 2158?
Public universities and colleges --Indiana --Bloomington --Administration --History --20th century.; Curriculum planning --Education (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington --History --20th century.; Carter, Byrum; Indiana University. Chancellor of the Bloomington Campus; Indiana University -- Administration -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington -- Administration -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University, Bloomington. Vice President of the Bloomington Campus -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Vice President of the Bloomington Campus -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Vice President of the Bloomington Campus -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. Chancellor of the Bloomington Campus -- Archives; Indiana University. Chancellor of the Bloomington Campus -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. Chancellor of the Bloomington Campus -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Carter, Byrum -- Archives; Carter, Byrum -- Correspondence
- Administrative subject files, 1963-1976 (Box 1)
  - AAUP, Association of University Professors, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Academic Affairs, Dean for (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Academic Appointments, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Academic Handbook, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Academic Policy and Program Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Academic Priorities (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 1)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Committee (Box 1)
      - 1969 (Box 1)
      - 1970 (Box 1)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Committee Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Official Papers, Drafts, etc., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Task Force, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Committee Minutes (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Communications (Box 1)
    - General, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Carter, 1972-75 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Communicators, 1971 (Box 1)
  - AdCom., September 3, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Committee (Box 1)
    - Agenda Items and General (Box 1)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Coordinator file, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Personnel (Box 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Adult Education, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee for the Chancellor (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee to the Chancellor on Tenure, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Natural Areas, Bloomington, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee for the Student Health Service, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Affirmative Action Program, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    (Restricted Materials Removed)
  - Afro-American Affairs, 1971- 1975 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Affairs Office, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Affairs, Vice Chancellor for (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Program, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Allen, Joel, 1969-1970; (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Allied Health (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1973 (Box 2)
    - 1975 (Box 2)
  - Allied Health Sciences Program Committee, Bloomington, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Office, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Animal Care Advisory Committee, Bloomington, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Annual Space Inventory, September 3, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Appointments and Payroll Procedures for Graduate Students, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - October-December 1972 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Arts and Sciences Curriculum Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 2)
  - Assembly Hall (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Assembly Hall, University Events Building Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
  - Associate College, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Associate Instructors (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - November 1971 (Box 2)
  - Associate Instructor Hearing Board, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Astronomy, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - Athletics (Box 2)
    - 1963-1973 (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Auditorium (Box 2)
    - General (Box 2)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
      - 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Policy Committee, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
    - Series Committee, 1963-1970 (Box 2)
  - Auxiliary Enterprise, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Authorized Signatures for Approving Payroll and Requisitions, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Average Fall Credit Hour per Faculty FTE, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Baccalaureate, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - Ballantine, 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Beck Chapel, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Biennial Budget, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Biennium Budget, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
  - Big 10, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Biographical Materials (Oscar Ross Ewing), 1969 (Box 3)
  - Biological Sciences (Box 3)
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Division of (Box 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - Black Laboratory of Archaeology, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Bloomington Campus Promotions Committee, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Bloomington, City of, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - Board of Academic Review, 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - Board Agenda (Box 3)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 3)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 3)
  - Board Agenda and AdCom., 1974 (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees (Box 3)
    - General (Box 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3)
      - 1972-1975 (Box 3)
      - December 1975 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1975; (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bookstore (Box 3)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Bookstore Policy Advisory Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - Boycott, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Budget (Box 3)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Budget Deficit, September 20, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Budget History, IUB, 1972-1975 (Box 3)
  - Budget Information, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - Budget Preparation Schedule, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Budget Process, Steps on, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Budget Request Forms, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Budget Request Worksheets, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Budget Summary/Analysis of FY '75, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, Miscellaneous, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Budgetary Procedures to Effect Savings, New, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Bureau of Educational Studies and Testing, 1971-1975 (Box 4)
  - Bureau of Public Discussion, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Bursar, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Bus, campus, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Business (Old), undated (Box 4)
  - Business Manager (Box 4)
    - Undated (Box 4)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 4)
  - Business, School of (Box 4)
    - Annual Report of the Dean, July 27, 1970 (Box 4)
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - General, February 1971-November 1972 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Academic Affairs (CAA), 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Cable Television, 1971 (Box 4)
  - CAD (Council of Chancellors), 1970 (Box 4)
  - Cadet Program, IU Safety, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Calendar, University (Box 4)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 4)
  - Campus Bus Advisory Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 4)
  - Campus Computer Use Committee, Bloomington, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Campus Facilities Office, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Campus Mail, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Campus Ministry Board, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Campus Planning Committee (Box 4)
    - 1970 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1975 (Box 4)
  - Career Counseling, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Carter, Byrum (Box 4)
    - Appreciation and Thank You Notes, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Congratulatory Letters, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Congratulatory Message, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - Meetings, Trips, etc. (Box 4)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 4)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 4)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Memos to Faculty, etc., 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - North Central Association (Box 4)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1975 (Box 4)
    - Press Releases, 1969-1973 (Box 4)
    - Speeches, Responses to, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - State of the Campus Address, Responses to, 1970 (Box 4)
    - State of the Campus Address, Responses to, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Travel, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
    - Center for Research Libraries, 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Chancellor's Office, Intern, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Chemistry (Box 5)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - Civil Rights, December 1972- March 1975 (Box 5)
  - Classical Archaeology Program (Box 5)
    - General, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Schrader Gift, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Classics Department, 1972-1975 (Box 5)
  - Classical Studies, 1971-1976 (Box 5)
  - Commission on Graduation Requirements, Report of, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Committees (Box 5)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 5)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - A-H, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - I-W, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Committee Appointments (Box 5)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 5)
  - Committee on the Arts, 1967-1970 (Box 5)
  - Committee to Beautify Campus, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Committee for Campus Counseling Services, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Committee Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Equality of Educational Opportunities, Bloomington, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Committee Membership Suggestions, March 6, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Student Membership, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Committees No Longer Under BEC's Auspices, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Communications Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 5)
  - Communications Committee, Search/Screening Committee, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Communications Director, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
  - Communications Task Force, APC, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Comparison of Actual vs. Est. Enrollments, September 19, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Compensation for 1972 Summer Session (Box 5)
    - General, August 5, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Amendment, September 20, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Complaints, 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Computer Assisted Instructions, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Computer Use, 1971-1975 (Box 5)
  - Conference Bureau (Box 5)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Conference Bureau Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Confidential, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Continuation Justification Review, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Continuing Education, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Continuing Education, Division (Box 6)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Continuing Studies, 1974; (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Contract Administration, 1970-1974 (Box 6)
  - Control Data Corp., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Controller, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Construction, 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - Convertible Lectureships (Box 6)
    - September 30, 1971 (Box 6)
    - October 25, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Convocations Committee, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Cooperative Education, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Coordinator for School Science, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Coordinator for Science, Search and Screen, September 1973-March 1974 (Box 6)
  - Coordinators (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - Corporate Police Power, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Counseling, 1972-1975 (Box 6)
  - Course Proposing to Use Human Subjects, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Course Reservation, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Creole Petroleum Gift, Committee to Administer the, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Criteria and Procedures for Identifying Employees, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Curriculum, 1972-1975 (Box 6)
  - Cummins, Margaret, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    (Restricted)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Dates for Salary Checks, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Data Processing, 1972-1975 (Box 6)
  - Dawson, Janna, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Day Care Centers, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Dean of Faculties, Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Dean of Students (Box 6)
    (Restricted materials removed)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Dean's Retreat, 1971- 1974 (Box 6)
  - Degree Program Proposals, Regional Campuses, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Degree Proposal Review Committee, All Universities, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Departmental Development Awards, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Departmental Fellowships, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Disadvantaged Students, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Disaster Control, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Discrimination (Box 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 6)
  - Distinguished Ranks, 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - Draft Letters (Box 6)
    - September 1972- December 1975 (Box 6)
    - Klinge for Carter (Box 6)
    - Turner for Carter, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Drug Arrests Information, Confidential, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Drug Education, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Drug Education Program, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Dues, 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - East Asian Report and Proposal to Upgrade, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Education (Old), 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Education, School of (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Educational Conferences, Committee on, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Electricity, Postage, and Telephone Costs, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Enrollment and Credit Hour Statistics, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Enrollment Statistics (Box 7)
    - 1970 (Box 7)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 7)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Action Day, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Health, Committee on (Box 7)
    - 1969 (Box 7)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Health and Safety (Box 7)
    - General, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Laboratory, Sub-Committee, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Studies, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Teaching Steering Committee, Ad Hoc, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Equal Employment, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
  - Equipment Committee (Box 7)
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 7)
    - Academic and Administrative, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Maintenance, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Equipment Requests, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Equity Adjustments, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Evaluation of Rank Committee, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Ewing Philosophy Prize Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - External Degree, 1971- 1975 (Box 7)
  - Faculties, Dean of (Box 8)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Communications, Committee on, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Council, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Council, Bloomington, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Manuel, August 22, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Members, Sabbatical Leaves (Box 8)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Newsletters, 1971-1976 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Records, July 1972-March 1975 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Recruitment Policy, November 17, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Salaries (Box 8)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Status of IU Libraries, 1971- 1974 (Box 8)
  - Fall Registration and Counseling, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Fee Increases, 1969-1973 (Box 8)
  - Fee Reduction and Remission for Graduate Students, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Fee Remission (ad hoc), 1969 (Box 8)
  - Fee Remission Awards, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Fee, Correction to Dept. Fee Remission Memo Award, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Fee Remission Awards and Fellowships, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Fee Remissions, Scholarships, Fellowship Task Force, APC, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Fees, Bloomington, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Fine Arts Department, 1971-1975 (Box 8)
  - Fine Arts Museum, 1970-1975 (Box 8)
  - Focus Program, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Ford Foundation, Report to East Asian Studies, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Students, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Student Advisory Committee (Box 8)
    - 1969 (Box 8)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Foreign Study Committee, 1964-1970 (Box 8)
  - Forensic Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Foster Essay Prize Committee, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Forster Project, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Founder's Day, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - Fraternity Housing Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - Fraternity Housing Planning Committee, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Fraternity and Sorority Affairs, Committee on, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Fringe Benefits, 1970-1973 (Box 8)
  - Funding of Evening Courses at Bloomington, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Geology (Box 8)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Geography, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - German, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Germanic Languages, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  - General Correspondence and Memoranda, 1969-1973; (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Gifts to IU (Box 8)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Governance, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Grading, December 1970-1974 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Assistants - Data (Box 8)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Assistant Salaries, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Library School, Old, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Graduate Residence Center, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Graduate School, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Grants, Faculty Course Development, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Grievance Panel, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Group Programs, 1969-1973 (Box 9)
  - Guidelines (Box 9)
    - 1971 (Box 9)
    - 1973 (Box 9)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Halls of Residence (Box 9)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 9)
    - May 1971-October 1971 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Halls of Residence Committee, 1963-1971 (Box 9)
  - Handicapped, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Health, Student Health Center Policy Committee, Ad Hoc, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, 1970-1975 (Box 9)
  - Health, Physical Education, and Recreation (HPER), School of (Box 9)
    - Undated (Box 9)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 9)
  - Health Professions, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Health Professions Committee, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Health and Safety, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Heraldic Banners, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Hearing Officers (Box 9)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 9)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 9)
  - Higher Education Commission (Box 9)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 9)
    - 1973-1974, (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9)
    - 1973-1974, (folder 2 of 2) (Box 10)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 10)